HEBER BERMUDEZ

Statistician - Colombian

hebermudezg@gmail.com \(\display \) hebermudezg@unal.edu.co \(\display (+57)3115604078 \) https://hebermudezg.com/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Statistician with a special focus on applied statistics and epidemiological data analysis, I experience collecting, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting quantitative information, providing insight and recommendations on policies and strategies. I have worked in data visualization for business intelligence, written reports, development and implementation of predictive models, database management and software development. I possess strong IT and analytical skills, as well as the interpersonal and communication skills to share findings with colleagues and clients. I apply statistical theories and methods to solve practical problems in a range of sectors, including; engineering, science, education, the environment, health, transportation, software companies, among others. I love music, chess, data science, arificial intelligence, and science popularization.

EDUCATION

National University of Colombia.

2015-2021, Medellín, Colombia.

Undergraduate in Statistics.

GPA: 4.1/5.0

SENA. 2013-2014, Ibagué, Colombia.

Technologist in industrial production managemen.

SENA. 2010-2011, Ibagué, Colombia.

Technician in analysis, design and software development.

EXPERIENCE

International cultural exchange.

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021, Custer, SD, United States.

 Participated in a cultural exchange program as a student to strengthen English skills and learn about American culture.

Infection and Cancer Research Group.

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021, Medellín, Colombia.

Internship as Epidemiological data analyst, Antioquia University.

- Supported statistical analyzes of epidemiological and biomedical data for research projects.
- Research collaborator, creation of written reports of findings.

Unalytics, Research incubator.

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020, Medellín, Colombia.

Assistant student, National University of Colombia.

- Founded and managed a research incubator where lead a group of 15 people, the group was attached to the school of statistics as a pedagogical strategy.
- Taught theoretical and practical skills in the area of applied statistics, data science, machine learning and artificial intelligence.
- Coordinated academic products for participation in contests, congresses and colloquiums. See more: https://unalyticsteam.github.io/unalytics/

Biosuplies SAS.

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015, Ibagué, Colombia.

SENA Intern, Biosuplies SAS

- Created forms and process manuals as well as software programs to automate administrative tasks such as stock management and quality control.
- Developed software that allows fast, easy and effective prescription of masterly medicines, which was distributed among the main Hospitals allied with the company in municipalities of Colombia.
- Participated in the laboratory certification visit that was carried out by the National Institute for Food and Drug Surveillance.

PUBLICATIONS

Journals papers in review.

• Comparison of the clinical performance of the lower-cost (Hybribio-H13) and HC2 HPV tests for detection of CIN2+ and CIN3+. Maria Cecilia Agudelo, Samuel Agudelo, Gloria Inés Sánchez, et al. Cancer Investigation jorunal, March 2022, acknowledgment **Esteban Bermudez**

Conference notes.

Text mining to study some terminologies about data science in Colombia.
 Heber Esteban Bermudez, Karen Andrea Amaya, Yubar Marín, René Palomino.
 https://acortar.link/Hdgr3S

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

Student Representative.

2019

Student representative of the Conflict Resolution and Disciplinary Aspects Committee of the Faculty of Sciences of the National University of Colombia, dedemocratically elected by vote.

Best degree project.

2011

Technical College, Best degree project related to software programming.

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

XIII National statistics colloquium

2021

Attendant, National University of Colombia.

XII National statistics colloquium

2019

Speaker, Web application, Machine Learning for text analysis, National University of Colombia.

XXIX International statistical symposium

2019

2019

Speaker, Text mining to study some terminologies about data science in Colombia, Northern University.

Dataton BC

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank. Modeling of credit risk from the digital trace, top 20% Kaggle Challenge.

Dataton BC 2018

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank. Text mining to identify expenses by categories.

CERTIFICATIONS, MOOCS

Artificial Intelligence for medicine. Coursera, Deeplearning.ai	2022
AWS S3 Basics. Coursera	2022
SQL for Data science. Coursera, DAVIS University	2021
Structuring Machine Learning Projects. Coursera, Deeplearning.ai	2020
Neural Networks and Deep Learning. Coursera, Deeplearning.ai	2020
$ \begin{array}{c} \textbf{Tableau Public for Project Management.} \\ \textit{Coursera} \end{array} $	2020
Introduction to data science. Coursera, Autonomous University of Mexico	2020

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming	R, Python, Java, Visual Basic, React Native.
Databases	SQL .
Version control tools	Git, GitHub.
Data Visualization, BI	Power BI, Tableau.
Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence	Pandas, Scikit-learn, Tidyverse, Tensorflow, Pytorch.
Typesetting Document	Latex.

LANGUAGES

English Intermediate.Spanish Native.